Michael Vincent

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Hello! I am a software engineer, frontend developer, and designer with 2.5 years of experience developing full-stack mobile and web applications in the New York City startup space. Also, upon first arriving in Brooklyn from Texas, I taught sixth grade mathematics.

I'm looking for software engineer and frontend developer roles based in NYC or remote. I specialize in product development and bringing user-facing designs and functionality to life, and have also worked extensively across the entire stack.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer | TaxBit

October 2022 - June 2024

- Scalability Contributed to a large-scale project overhauling our database management, expanding our API layer, and eliminating on-the-fly calculations to handle larger data volume
 - The project increased maximum data volume from ~300K transactions to millions, and improved load times from minutes to ~15 seconds.
- **Product Development** Collaborated with design and project managers to scope, build, and release redesigned dashboard, contacts, and settings pages
 - · Compartmentalized components into a reusable design system
- Coverage Modernized our React frontend to include Typescript and expanded our E2E and unit testing
 - Increased Typescript coverage from 0% to 70%

Software Engineer | Envogue International

January 2022 - October 2022

- **Design** Collaborated closely with product design to create initial page wireframes for early stage startup Madeyn, and then implemented them on mobile
 - Helped design and implement post creation flow, profile pages, and home pages
- Consistency Maintained consistency between iOS, Android, and website frontend development and design through partnerships with frontend and data engineers on the team
 - · Launched multiple new iOS and Android versions
- Leadership Aided heavily in transitioning our issue tracking into Jira, following Agile design practices
 - · Scoped up to 3 months ahead for frontend projects

Associate Teacher | Success Academy Charter Schools

June 2021 - January 2022

- Leadership Managed 30+ students simultaneously in both remote and in-person environments
- **Dealing with Pressure** Developed strong skills in conflict resolution and problem solving through classroom management

michaelvincent.io

mvincent121212@gmail.com

325-212-1333

Brooklyn, NY

EDUCATION

2021 | B.S. Honors | 3.82 GPA

Chemical Engineering
UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT AUSTIN

Organizations - Tau Beta Pi Engineering Honors Society, American Institute for Chemical Engineers, Texas Undergraduate Moot Court

SKILLS

Typescript / Javascript
React
HTML / CSS
Python
Flask
Django
PostgreSQL
AWS (EC2, Athena, S3, ELB)

Jest

Playwright

TOOLS

Figma, Jira, Confluence, Google Sheets/Excel, Apache Airflow, Google Cloud Platform, Firebase

SOCIAL

linkedin.com/in/mvincent12